<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Zak Turner</title><link>https://zakturner.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Zak Turner</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 16:51:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zakturner.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Is it My Responsibility to Help the Widows and Orphans?</title><link>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/32560744-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 16:51:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/32560744-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</guid><description>The question of whether taking responsibility for helping widows and orphans is solely up to the individual being posed depends upon one's belief systems, moral perspectives as well as cultural values. This topic entails sensitive issues relating to personal beliefs on morality, philanthropy, societal obligations, and spiritual teachings. For a better understanding of the subject matter, let us analyze different belief systems and how they guide an individual in taking responsibility towards widows and orphan care.</description></item><item><title>Why Christians Can Be Bad at Being Kind</title><link>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/27082347-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 16:36:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/27082347-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</guid><description>It might seem counterintuitive that Christians could be bad at one of the primary tenets of their faith: kindness. However, being a follower of Christ doesn't always equate to perfect behavior or virtuous actions. The reasons why Christians might struggle in being kind are numerous but often stem from misunderstanding God’s grace and love for humanity. In this article, we will explore these underlying factors while acknowledging how Christians can strive to improve their kindness towards others.</description></item><item><title>Self-Care: Selfish Habit or Holy Endeavor?</title><link>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/47787088-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 07:23:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/47787088-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</guid><description>To self-care or not to self-care, that is the question. It seems this concept is gaining traction as a powerful form of social action in our lives today, and with good reason—we need it as individuals and in community. If selflessness has been hailed by many religious and secular societies for millennia as a noble characteristic, how do we integrate self-care into our life narrative in way that remains true to our values and ethics?</description></item><item><title>Guilt and the Great Deception in the Christian Life</title><link>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/45487422-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 11:16:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/45487422-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</guid><description>In this blog post, we will explore how guilt can be a form of deception in the life of a Christian. While the Holy Spirit convicts us when we have genuinely wronged others or failed to follow God’s commands, Satan often uses false feelings of guilt to keep believers from moving forward in their walk with Christ and serving Him freely. We need discernment and Godly counsel to weed out manipulative guilt from genuine conviction.</description></item><item><title>4 Keys to Building Confidence in God When Life Falls Apart</title><link>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/60034755-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 19:46:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/60034755-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</guid><description>Trial and error is a critical part of human life but sometimes the trials come with such magnitude that it seems impossible to get up again. At moments like these, trusting God becomes the most daunting task and a key need to survive. This article speaks about how one can build confidence in God in trying times when life falls apart.
1. Stay Connected to God through Prayer Speaking to God is one way we can stay close despite what we are going through.</description></item><item><title>How Should Christians Approach Progress in Technology?</title><link>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/38948441-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 07:18:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/38948441-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</guid><description>The Christian approach to technology should be well-thought-out and balanced. This means that we must consider both the benefits of technological advancements and the potential challenges they bring. In this article, we will discuss how Christians can navigate and approach progress in technology with wisdom and discernment. We will explore several key ideas including understanding God's creative nature, evaluating the impact on humanity, being aware of potential dangers or consequences, maintaining balance in our lives, using technology for God's glory, and cultivating humility as we engage with new developments.</description></item><item><title>Why Are There So Many Ideas about Heaven That Are Not Biblical?</title><link>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/44957264-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 13:07:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/44957264-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</guid><description>The idea of heaven permeates our cultural and religious imaginations, but many conceptions of it are not based on biblical texts. This article aims to explore why there are so many non-biblically sound ideas about heaven. Some contributing factors include the influence of paganism, Platonic philosophy, Gnosticism, the liminal nature of heavenly concepts, cultural syncretism, the historical development of Christian eschatology, individual interpretations, and sectarian movements. While Scripture provides the primary foundation for Christian understanding of heaven, these factors have contributed significantly to various misconceptions about its nature.</description></item><item><title>Why Should Christians Evaluate What Their Lives Are Built On?</title><link>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/18446587-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 16:40:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/18446587-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</guid><description>In a world where truth and wisdom are often blurred by selfishness, deception, or apathy, it is critical for every person to regularly examine the fundamental building blocks of their lives. This exercise is particularly crucial for Christian believers who seek to walk faithfully before God and actively serve Him. Proverbs 4:23 provides this directive: “Guard your heart above all else, for it determines the course of your life.” There are four key reasons why Christians ought to diligently evaluate what their lives are built on:</description></item><item><title>One Key Reason Why Church Consultations Fail</title><link>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/64745730-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 05:49:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/64745730-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</guid><description>As a church consultant, I have witnessed a wide array of situations during my time working with churches. While every congregation is unique in its makeup, challenges faced, and growth potential, there are common issues that underlie many of the failures experienced when attempting to improve church health and effectiveness through consultation practices. In this article, we will explore one key reason why many church consultations fail: poor self-assessment skills within leadership teams.</description></item><item><title>9 Lessons for New Christians ... And Old Ones</title><link>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/99849678-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 06:28:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/99849678-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</guid><description>Whether you are new to the Christian faith or have been following Jesus for years, it's always beneficial to remember some key lessons that will help strengthen your faith. Some of these may seem basic but all are essential to really living out Christianity. Let's take a look at nine important lessons that apply universally to both new and experienced Christians alike.
1. Develop an Intimate Relationship with God through Prayer and Scripture Meditation At the heart of being a Christian is engaging in prayer and reading the Bible regularly to grow closer to God.</description></item><item><title>Why Do Christians Emphasize Hell Instead of Not Being with God in Heaven?</title><link>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/18083747-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 14:12:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/18083747-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</guid><description>Some critics of Christianity ask why Christians place such emphasis on hell rather than focusing only on the positive aspect of eternal union with God. In essence, the question is whether Christians give insufficient attention to not being excluded from heaven and highlighting hell instead. The answer is quite complex but centers primarily upon biblical contexts and subsequent practical implications concerning Christian faith in everyday life. Before diving into the details, though, let's define key concepts.</description></item><item><title>What Does Jesus Teach Us about God's End-Times Plan?</title><link>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/79312239-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 19:57:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/79312239-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</guid><description>Perhaps no other topic invites so much speculation and debate as the issue of when Christ will return in glory and establish His kingdom on earth (commonly referred to as “end times”). A plethora of views on this subject exist, ranging from optimistic predictions of exact dates to skepticism regarding the possibility or significance of Christ’s second coming altogether.
In order to understand Jesus' teachings regarding end times, it is crucial to view them within their original context; that is to say, we should look at His pronouncements during His time on earth while accounting for historical events and cultural practices prevalent during those days.</description></item><item><title>Why the Church Should Take Responsibility for Its Liberties and Freedoms</title><link>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/59287164-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 09:10:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/59287164-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</guid><description>In America, as in many other countries where religious liberty is enshrined in law or practice, there remains a kind of tension between government—particularly those actors charged with upholding secular laws—and religious bodies. While the tensions can manifest themselves in different ways (e.g., funding disputes between faith-based schools and their local authorities), one primary area of conflict seems to hinge upon how religious bodies understand their own responsibilities for both preserving their own liberties and freedoms while not encroaching on those same liberties for others.</description></item><item><title>How to Actually Treat Other Believers Like Family</title><link>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/81924229-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 15:51:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/81924229-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</guid><description>As believers, God calls us to be different in how we treat one another. We are not bound by strict hierarchy or status; rather, the Bible teaches us to be a tight-knit community where we relate to each other as family members. This article discusses practical ways to apply Christian love toward fellow believers, building a strong and healthy church body.
Share Your Life Together Fostering close relationships within the Christian community requires intentionality.</description></item><item><title>Why Pastors Struggle to Ask for Help (And How to Get Past It)</title><link>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/57546078-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 11:28:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/57546078-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</guid><description>As a pastor, I know firsthand how difficult it can be at times to ask for help when facing challenges. Whether it's due to pride, fear of weakness, or a belief that pastoral roles entail managing all problems independently, the hesitation is real. However, as leaders who serve their communities spiritually and emotionally, we must overcome this reluctance and learn to ask for assistance. This article explores some common reasons behind pastors' reluctance to seek help and offers practical ways to move beyond those obstacles.</description></item><item><title>Why People Are Losing Their Religion (and How the Church Can Respond)</title><link>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/40440663-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 08:20:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/40440663-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</guid><description>In recent years, we have seen a growing decline in religious affiliation across multiple regions. According to surveys conducted by Pew Research Center, the global percentage of people who identify as Christian has dropped from 86% in 1900 to just under three-quarters in 2010.^{[1]} This trend is also evident among younger generations with Millennials demonstrating a striking departure from their parents and grandparents’ religiosity levels. In the United States alone, only 39% of young adults aged 18–23 belong to any religion—a significant drop when compared with figures for older generations.</description></item><item><title>The Good and the Bad of Christian Fundamentalism</title><link>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/84350545-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 10:36:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakturner.github.io/posts/84350545-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</guid><description>Fundamentalism is a religious movement within Christianity that insists upon a highly literal interpretation of scripture. While there are many denominations within the Christian tradition, Christian Fundamentalism in particular has some unique characteristics that define it as a subcategory of conservative Protestantism. Some aspects of fundamentalist views can be beneficial, while others have negative effects both for its adherents and society at large. As with any deeply held belief system, understanding these elements can illuminate why people choose to align themselves with fundamentalism and help the dialogue between varying groups.</description></item></channel></rss>